this strategy that I'm going to be
teaching you in this video is so simple
and so effective that if used properly
you can make money in the markets every
single day from this video on forward
and this strategy is called shift of
structure and for me personally I use it
in every single one of my trades and it
makes me anywhere from 50 to $100,000
per trade that I take using my shift of
structure and these numbers that you're
seeing right here this is by simply
applying what I'm going to teach you in
this video starting now so you're
probably wondering what does shift of
structure mean well it's pretty simple
because it's literally what it means
it's a shift of structure in the market
so the market when it is going in an
uptrend it consists of structure every
single high point and every single low
point that is considered a structure
Point all of these random points in the
chart where price has a rejection and
then it just fluctuates up and down each
and every single one of those elbows or
triangles those are points of structure
this is where the market is giving you
the indication that we are now in a
bullish Trend or if we are on a bearish
trend obviously if we're heading to the
downside so what is the shift structure
well it's literally when there's a shift
of structure when you can see that these
elbows to the upside are no longer going
to the upside now they have shifted and
started going to the downside same thing
as if you're in a bearish market and
then you see the shift of structure
shifting now to the upside it's when the
structure completely changes Direction
in the market and you're probably
wondering when does this happen right so
this pattern happens in two different
scenarios the first scenario is let's
say if the market is heading to the
upside meaning that you are having a
bullish structure and it's been going on
for a long time the market starts to
slow down that's where you can then see
a shift of structure and you can see the
market have a reversal and shift
structure to the downside so that's the
first one the second one is when Market
hits a very strong resistance level and
then you have the shift of structure
then now makes price reverse obviously
same thing vice versa to then if the
market is heading to the downside the
market has been heading to the downside
for a very long time and it starts to
slow down that's where you can then see
a shif of structure and the market can
now start heading to the upside or if we
hit a very strong support level and at
that support level the market rejects
from it shift the structure and now
we're now heading to the upside so this
might seem a little bit confusing
without the markets so let's actually
get into the markets right now let me
explain to you and let me show you what
a shift the structure looks like right
but before we get into there keep in
mind that the shift the structure
happens across all time frames 15 minute
30 minute 1 Hour 4 hour daily weekly the
shift of structure happens on every
single time frame but rule of thumb is
that the higher the time frame the more
the shift of structure is going to be
respected when you have a shift of
structure on The Daily it's obviously
going to have a bigger impact on the
market versus if there's a shift of
structure on the 15 minutes so that's a
rule of thumb and something to keep in
note so now you can see in this chart
right here there's a lot of different
patterns there's a lot of things going
on in this market right here first
things first you can see how this Market
was then headed to the downside at one
point and then at another point it then
headed to the upside and at this heading
to the upside then it headed to the
downside again and then from this
downside move then it headed to the
upside and then after heading to the
upside then it headed to the downside
every single one of these legs of it
moving up and down there's a complete
shift of structure the market literally
goes from bearish to bullish from
bullish to bearish about three four
times in this whole entire move and it's
actually very easy to understand once
you get to see it but before actually
showing the cam sticks I'm going to show
you in a line chart what it consists of
which is much better and effective as
you guys can tell this is a bearish
market a bearish market consist of lower
highs and lower lows these were the
elbows that I was talking to about or
the triangles this is what is considered
a structure point in the market this is
what it looks like on a line chart and
this is what it looks like on a bar
chart so every single one of these
elbows or triangles this right here is
Market structure this is a market
structure point this is a market
structure Point all of these are simple
Market structure points where price is
going to use it to have a rejection from
to then head to the upside or head to
the downside and based off of these
structure points is where we can see if
the market shifts to the upside or
shifts to the downside again might be
information overload but now I'm going
to get into a little bit more detail so
you guys have an idea and understand
what I'm explaining so you guys can see
right here that this is a bearish market
because this is a lower high and a lower
low lower high High lower low lower high
lower low so to make it very clear to
mark it off every single time you want
to see clear a shift of structure simply
mark it off so this right here would be
your lower high and then this point down
here would be your lower low so every
single time you have a lower high and a
lower low literally it is impossible for
there to be a shift of structure without
the market actually Shifting the
structure if price breaks Above This
lower high this is what is considered a
shift of structure if price makes it to
this point right here this as of right
now is not a shift of structure this
Market is still currently bearish
because there is still a lower high and
a lower low if this market right here
then does this then this would be a new
lower low and then this last point would
become the last lower high and the
market continues to head to the downside
like this when the market does something
like this this is not the lower high
because the market has not created a
lower low it is impossible for you to
have a lower high without a lower low
rule of thumb this cannot be a lower
high because then where would the lower
low be there's no lower low the lower
low would have to be the new lowest low
point in the chart it's very
self-explanatory so as of right now all
of this has been continuous bearish
momentum in the market there's no no
shift of structure now this right here
once again is absolutely nothing it's
just a structure point in the market
there's no shift of structure the shift
of structure is when you literally shift
this structure point right here Market
can do this and do this and this is
still not a lower high because there is
no lower low again it is impossible to
have a lower high without a lower low
and this right here is not a higher low
because we haven't shifted the market
structure so this right here is simply
just structure within the bearish trend
same thing if this does this right here
again this is not a shift of structure
because a shift of structure is only
when we body close above this structure
point right here now the moment we do
body close above this line now this time
frame has shifted to bullish this is now
a shift of structure so this bearish
structure in this market has now shifted
bullish so this right here would then
become the higher
high and then this down here would then
become the higher low the higher low is
literally the last higher low so now
this Market is in a bullish Market
structure the same thing applies as the
downtrend whenever you create a new
higher high the higher low follows it's
very simple and again the moment we body
close under this move this is now
bearish this would now be another shift
of structure but if the market has a
pull back to about right right here as
of right now this is still bullish
because we still haven't body closed
under this structure point so we are
still bullish so we continue the trend
going to the upside even if we do
something like this this is not a higher
high because we haven't created a high
above the last high so it's impossible
for it to be a higher high it literally
has hasn't gone higher above than that
last high but if we do have a higher
high then the new highest high becomes
the higher low and then you simply
follow the last structure point and then
boom this becomes the last higher low
this right here is still nothing the
moment we create Above This is now the
higher high and then this is the higher
low now the moment we body close under
this higher low structure point we are
now bearish this Market has now shifted
to the downside so this becomes the
lower low and then the last point which
is the last lowest high point becomes
the lower high again remember you cannot
have a lower low without a lower high
and you cannot have a higher low without
a higher high it's literally impossible
so now this market right here let's say
it does this and it body closes above
this well now we're bullish again cuz we
have just broken Above This lower high
structure point so this time frame right
now has become bullish and this is now
the new highest high point and exactly
how I just said it's impossible to have
a higher high without a higher low so
this right here would be a higher low
point and now this Market can now
continue heading to the upside and then
this would become a higher high it's
impossible to have a higher high without
a higher low so if this is the new
higher high there has to be a new higher
low it always changes when you have a
new higher high so again the moment this
body closes under this is now bearish
and then this becomes now the lower low
and then this over here becomes the
lower high so this what you guys have
just seen in front of you is a shift of
structure by you being able to see the
shift of structure You can predict what
is going to happen next because the
shift of structure usually happens first
on the lower time frames indicating to
you what's going to happen on the higher
time frames so this right here is a
perfect example of what is the shift of
structure so now I'm going to show you
what it looks like on the actual
Candlestick patterns so you guys can see
exactly what I'm explaining to you you
can almost predict what is going to
happen next because of the patterns that
it gives you so now we're going to move
the same exact shift of structure that
we just did on the line chart but to the
actual candlesticks that it's what we
trade and you can almost see that the
pattern that I have done right here is
the same exact pattern as what we have
done right here if I simply just zoom
out the chart a little bit and what I do
is I'm just going to grab this you know
sphere put it here you guys can see it's
basically this move right here to the
downside if I grab this sphere right
here and I put it up here you guys can
see it's that move I grab this sphere
right here and then I grab it and I put
it here you guys can see how it's
literally going to be the same exact
move so it's going to be very simple and
very effective so this right here is
going to be simple this is now bearish
why is it bearish well let me show you
guys you guys can see how we start off
the lower high point up here this is a
lower high lower low lower high and then
lower low so what we're going to do is
we're going to get our trusty lower high
line and then we're going to get our
trusty lower low Line This Way We Know
what is a lower high and what is a lower
low so once we have a lower low the
market then does this pullback and we
body close under this immediately turns
into the new lower low so this right
here is the lower low we body close
under and now we take it all the way to
the last point which will be right here
so this is now the last lower high which
would be this point right here and then
you follow this up and then where it
turns this then turns into the lower
high so this would be the lower high
this would be the lower low so now again
price could have came all the way back
up into here and then then this and we
could have still been bearish but what
we did is that we body closed under that
line so now this becomes the lower low
and then this becomes the lower high
this structure point right here we
pulled up all the way up to that lower
high point we never body closed above so
cool that doesn't mean that anything
happened that's Market is still bearish
but then we body closed under so now
this is the new lower low and then this
point right here becomes a lower high
again you just follow this little move
boom as soon as it turns this becomes
now the lower high but what tends to
happen here the market instead of coming
back up to the lower high point and then
heading to the downside it shifted the
structure you can see how it now has
broken Above This lower high point right
here and then it has now shifted it so
so now what happens this becomes the
higher high let me just move this text
to the left so you guys can see it so
now this becomes the higher high point
and then where's the higher low you
follow the little line and then boom
this is the higher low point right here
it is literally the same example that I
just gave you guys right here it's the
same exact thing we have a lower low
market and then we body close Above This
is now the bullish move it is literally
the same exact move so now this is where
the market has shifted to bullish so
this is the higher high and now this
body right here has turned into the
higher low the moment we body close
above this line this now becomes the new
higher high so this is now the higher
high and then now this right here is the
higher low let's make this to the right
as well so it's I me to the left so it's
easier to spot so now this is the higher
low if you notice here we never body
close under these Wicks don't mean
anything because they're just Wicks
they're not bodies we are only looking
for the bodies to close above or close
under so it's a confirmation of a shift
of structure so as you can see right
here no body close above or under then
right here boom it closes above so we
Chase it all the way into price stops
which it stops right here so this is the
higher high we follow it down to where
then it has the rejection and now this
is the higher low so now you're seeing
how this Market has shifted from bearish
to now bullish so you could have entered
the trade right here beautifully once it
broke and retested the shifter structure
this is how you could have used the
shifter structure to enter the trade
because you can see how now we've come
into a strong level of support and we
have shifted the structure so this is
your indication to you like okay this
bearish move to the downside has
completely stopped so now we have a
shift of structure we have rejection
from an area of Interest we have bullish
engulfing Candlestick this is a good
high probability trade to take if you
don't know what a strong support area is
or what a bullish engulfing Candlestick
is make sure you watch these videos up
here cuz it explains those things into
great detail in order so you understand
how to implement the shift the structure
with a strong support and all these
things so you create a profitable
trading plan so you have an edge over
the market so we can continue this going
literally all day because the market all
it does is create Market structure every
single day so now that we have this
higher High Point Body Candlestick
closes above you can see right here how
then this is the higher high we follow
it down this would then turn into the
higher
low and then as you can tell this took
quite a while to then break above which
is actually very fast break above you
see that little minor line of the body
that it closed above that counts so that
is now the higher high follow it down
this is where it then shifts so this is
now the higher low point right here we
body Candlestick close under so now this
is bearish so this turns into the lower
low and then this over here turns into
to the lower high and you can literally
see how now from that shifter structure
right there how you could have predicted
this huge lower high bearish move to the
downside you add that in there with a
beautiful head and shoulders pattern
which again if you don't know what a
head and shoulders pattern is in click
this video right here to explains to you
perfectly what it what that is and how I
use it with my trading plan every single
day so you can see how the shift the
structure happens right in front of your
face and you can literally see what's
going to happen in the next moon move as
soon as you have a shift structure and
we can continue going this forever like
I'm not even kidding to market the
structure all the time so now here you
can see how we have a new lower low
point and then this is a lower high
point right here and I'm going to show
you how you can actually enter a trade
with Shi the structure just right in
front of your face so once you have a
lower low point we then have a new lower
low so this becomes a lower low point
right here and then the lower high point
becomes the last lower high point which
is this one so this is now the the lower
high and then as soon as we get a body
Candlestick closure above what do we
have a shift of structure so now that
you have a shift of structure this is
your indication that okay now we are
ready to be interested in taking this
trade and this is where we would then
wait for a higher low and then we would
wait for our bullish engulfing
Candlestick which is this pattern right
here so literally because of the shift
of structure this would have given us a
strong indication to take this trade so
we would have our ENT point right here
our stop loss always goes under the last
higher low because we want to make sure
we have enough space just in case if
this decides to pull back right to that
point create a double bottom and then
head to the upside because even if it
creates a double bottom it doesn't shift
to the downside cuz if it closes under
this line remember we are now bearish so
the trade was completely wrong you're
taking this trade because the market is
going to reverse so you want to have
your stop loss right under the zone that
if it does hit it your trade was
completely wrong and it wasn't just a
simple wakeout cuz if you have your
stop- loss right around here price can
still have a little bit deeper of a
pullback create a deeper higher low and
then head to the upside nobody wants to
get stopped out because of a wick out so
you want to make sure you have your stop
loss with enough breathing room so if it
decides to have a deeper higher low
you're still good so you would have
entered this trade literally right at
that bullish engulfing Candlestick and
you would have had an easy one to two
trade sell right at the resistance level
without any stress zero drop down and
simp using set and forget it is
literally that simple and this example
right here is the same exact example as
we did right here and it could have been
the same exact example that we could
have done for a cell right here as soon
as you see the shift structure wait for
the lower high or the higher low wait
for the engulfing Candlestick and you're
pretty much golden not going to lie and
I kid you not I use this pattern every
single day in the markets with my
personal traits and when I get on a call
every single week with my students that
is what I impli to them every single
week that they have to take a trade with
a shift to structure that's how my
students are making anywhere from $1,000
to $11,500 a week using my set and
forget strategy because you're using my
trading plan along with addition to the
shift of structure at the area of
Interest with my set and forget strategy
that lets him make anywhere from ,000 to
$1,500 a week as a beginner set and
forget Trader you're probably wondering
what is set and forget and you want to
know more about it just click the link
in the description below I have a video
there for you that is going to explain
everything about set and forget and how
making Traders make anywhere from ,000
to $1,500 a week as a beginner set
forget Trader just click the link in the
description below so you guys can see
what is Center forget about and what
does it even mean and how I can
incorporate it with my trading plan and
the shif the structure so I hope you
guys found this video useful and I'll
see you guys in the next video